

#### LINKS

#### LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/samujiwal-singh-chauhan-095961a7/

#### GitHub:

http://https://github.com/Samujjwal13

#### Blog:

http://https://cosmologywithsam.wordpress.com/

#### **ABOUT ME**

An experienced and innovative Data Scientist and Full stack ML engineer graduated in B. Tech (E.I.E) now working in GENPACT, whose continuing passion for the industry coupled with a desire to further his development through new and challenging projects is a desirable asset.

# SAMUJJWAL CHAUHAN

DATA SCIENTIST



Nagina Dhampur Road, Dhampur, 246761, India



09557729840



samujjwal13@gmail.com

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **GENPACT**

Noida Jan 2019 - Present

#### Data Scientist

GENAISYS (GENPACT ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE SYSTEM) is artificial intelligent system for financial Cash and receivables system used by GE (General Electric) where I implemented:

- Predictive Model for scoring the invoices on the basis of due dates and calculating propensity score for invoices to be paid within the due date.
- Applying the K-Means clustering for segmenting invoices for further optimizing collection process and reduce the manual labor time.
- Used feedback NLP engine for Mails Automation to reply the mail automatically after calculating the intent of the body and analyzing the feedback from manual users.

# 2. UNEECOPS TECHNOLOGIES LTD Noida

Sep 2018 - Dec 2021

#### Intern

CPMS (Comprehensive Pension Management System): CPMS is a seamless pension processing system for Department of telecommunication (DOT) India through integrated software, which would bring the processing, sanctioning, authorization and payment units under a common platform.

- Built Machine Learning Pipelines Using Airflow and AirBnB with Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAGs) of tasks.
- Worked on AWS EC2 instance having REHL Linux Machine to setup all the libraries required for Machine learning project.

# 3. BLUE UMBRELLA

Delhi May 2016 - Aug 2019

# Full Stack Developer

Status: compliance program technology & Automation: Status is the platform compliance. It is a compliance technology, focusing on automation and efficiency.

- Implemented state of the art Automation graphs for automating the compliance process.
- Developed the web app dashboard where user have the access of all the data to play with.

LEVELS: Compliance program technology & Automation: Levels is a mid-market modular plug and play Blue Umbrella GRC solution that simplifies the way organizations identify and communicate risk from third parties.

- Developed Passport verification application to validate the applied application.
- Optimized the SQL queries to
- Implemented Threading and Async programming to Optimize the Application to reduce TAT for user experience.

CYIENT

Intern

Noida Oct 2015 - Apr 2016

KPN telecom Network fiber and copper: Knowledge of GIS platform.

GEOS FOW Netviewer: the basic functions of give meaning to the data of the copper and fiber network for a correct interpretation.

GEOS DOCS: is Geospatial Data Science, the 3D data models recently play an important role in the research and visualization projects. QGIS is one of the most popular free and open-source cross-platform desktop GIS application software that every GIS geek knows.

#### **EDUCATION**

MIET, MEERUT

Meerut 2015

**Bachelor of Technology** 

Graduated with 70%

PRIYANKA MODERN

UP 2011 Intermediate

• Scored 78% marks (Dictation in Physics, Chemistry & Math)

PRIYANKA MODERN

2009

High school diploma

Attained 78% marks (Dictation Overall)

# **SKILLS**

PYTHON	SQL
ESSENTIAL MATH FOR DATASCIENCE	DATA SCIENCE
MACHINE LEARNING	ACTIVE LEARNING
DATA VISUALIZATION	ML.NET

### **COURSES**

O'REILLY MEDIA

Sep 2021 - Oct 2021

O'REILLY MEDIA Aug 2021 - Sep 2021

O'REILLY MEDIA

Jul 2021 - Aug 2021

O'REILLY MEDIA Jun 2021 - Jul 2021 Deep Learning with TensorFlow, Keras, and PyTorch

Data Structures, Algorithms, and Machine Learning Optimization

**Calculus for Machine Learning** 

Linear Algebra for Machine Learning